Hi, I'm Jeremy Blackwell, I'm here today to help you get started on your basement remodel project.
One thing to remember when plumbing your basement, is that the location of the toilet is not as important as it first may seem.
Where that pipe is sticking out of the concrete is not where it has to be.
It is possible to move that that plumbing to, to make a better space for your toilet.
There are certain restrictions though on where to set the toilet, so you want to make sure and take that into account when you're framing.
You've got to have your toilet fifteen and a half to sixteen inches at least from any finished surface so that there's room to get in and out of this confined space.
The the toilet flange itself must be off of the wall about twelve inches or so too, to, to have the toilet fit into the correct place.
Another common mistake that most homeowners make when finishing their own basement is they forget to put a fan in the bathroom.
The fan is very important because not only does it take the unsightly vapors out of the house, but it also takes any condensation that develops and vents it outside of the house.
This is also very important, don't forget the, the fan in the bathroom.
A lot of people when they're finishing their basement are concerned with the resale value of their home.
And if this is a concern for you, you want to make sure and have a shower and a bathtub in your basement bathroom.
The only problem is that you will not be able to fit a one piece tub and shower in some basements because of the way they've been built with the stairwell and you certainly can't fit it through a window.
So what we do in that case, is set a cast iron tub, or a material like cast iron and then just do a cultured marble or tile surround around the bathtub.